We've added in
functionality so that we can
actually have the player
run into our power-up,
and then on our player game object, you
can see that has power-up turns to true.
Now this power-up will be very
useful only for a specific circumstance.
When our player runs
into one of our spawned
enemies on our screen,
while we have the power-up.
Now one thing we want to make sure
we do, just to make our lives a bit easier,
is if we go into our pre-fab's folder,
if we double-click on our enemy,
we want to set their tags
to be enemy, so we'll add
a tag, make sure you add
a custom tag for enemy,
and then go back to the
enemy under the pre-fab window,
go to the tag section, add the enemy tag,
and then we can leave our pre-fab window.
So now we have a tag for our enemy.
Next we're going to go
into our player controller
script, and in our
player controller script,
we're actually going to create a new
method underneath On Trigger Enter,
so we're going to make an
On Collision Enter method.
Now the reason we actually want to use
On Collision Enter versus On Trigger Enter
is because On Trigger
Enter is useful when you are
just trying to understand
triggers between colliders.
But if you're trying to do something with
physics, you use On Collision Enter instead.
In our On Collision Enter
method, we're going to check again
for another condition, so
we need an F statement.
So if the object we're colliding
with is an enemy, and if
our player has the power up,
then we should do something.
In this case, we're just going to
use a debug.log statement for now,
so that way we know that it worked.
So if we debug.log, so that
way we can see in our console,
now we can type in a string,
so we'll say collided with.
And now what we're actually going to
do is something called concatenation.
So we can actually add strings together to
be able to create one entire full message.
So we have this first string that we
typed out literally using our quotes.
And now we actually want to know
the name of what we've collided with,
so we would get the
collision.gameobject.name.
And you see when we use
.name, we actually get a string back.
And then we use another plus sign.
And then another set of
quotes for a literal string again.
With power up, set two.
And then if we do a plus,
and then we use has power up.
So this will tell us, when we've collided
with whatever we collide with an enemy,
it will tell us that our power
up is set to true or false.
In this case, it'll be true because
we've added that in our if statement.
So you can actually use variables and
strings in an entire message for a debug.log.
So that way we have a string,
and then you add in another string,
and then you add in the
string literal once again.
And then you can even add in different
variables like Booleans or integers or floats.
If you're looking for
some precise information.
So now when we save this,
so in Unity, when we press play,
if we pick up the power up, and then
we hopefully collide with our enemy,
there you go. On the
bottom, you can see collided
with enemy clone with
power ups at the true.
Or if we check our console window,
you can see it up there as well.
So now it's your turn, you're
going to go into your enemy prefab.
Make sure you apply the enemy tag.
In our player controller script,
make sure that you add an
on collision enter method
into your player controller script.
In that on collision enter method, make sure
you add an if statement that will check.
If we collide with another
game object whose tag is enemy.
And we have a power
up, then we'll print out
this log statement to
tell us that we've collided
with an enemy while
our power up is activated.
Now it's your turn.